

# Alex Kio

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

#### **PROJECTS**

# Iron Mountain Website Redesign — Learn More

JUNE 2023 - PRESENT

We're creating a large component library using Next.js, Storybook, and Framer Motion. This library will be consumed by an instance of Sitecore Experience Manager and deployed across sixty international websites, some of which feature right-to-left orientation.

# Ogletree Deakins' Client Portal — Learn More

JANUARY 2023 - JUNE 2023

A Next.js application utilizing Contentful CMS, NextAuth, RTL & Jest, Sass, React Hook Form with Yup, React Table (Tanstack), React Query w/ Axios, & Radix UI components to deliver a secure front door to the client's valuable tools and content.

## **Ungork Design Services** — Learn More

JANUARY 2022 - JANUARY 2023

Talent support role on Unqork's Design Services team. Unqork is a "no-code" application development solution used by the likes of Goldman Sachs, Liberty Mutual, and the Cities of New York, Chicago and Washington DC.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Rightpoint — Developer 1 (L2)

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

I am a Front-End developer on the Product Experience team for this digital agency. We specialize in providing services related to digital strategy, design, and technology.

### **University of Florida** — Manager of Operations

DECEMBER 2017 - MARCH 2021

I was responsible for overseeing the daily operations of several National Institutes of Health (NIH) programs, which included assisting in process development and refinement, creating SOPs and procedure manuals, training employees, conducting quality-control audits, handling client services, and inventory management.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Turing School of Software & Design — Certificate in Front-End Software Engineering

MARCH 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

Turing is the sole accredited web development bootcamp in the U.S., offering intensive seven-month-long software development programs. Their Front-End program focuses on communication, collaboration, technical proficiency, and workflow best practices, incorporating user stories, wireframing, issue management, continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD), test-driven development (TDD), and code review. The tech stack for the Front-End program includes HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, and Cypress.

## **University of Florida** — Bachelor of Arts

JANUARY 2007 - MAY 2009

I graduated from the University of Florida with a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science and a minor in African Studies. During my academic tenure, I was an active member of our award-winning Model United Nations team and served as a board member for the Beta Gamma Chapter of Pi Sigma Alpha, the National Political Science Honor Society.